Guide to the Betsy Beinecke Shirley Collection of American Children's Literature
Beinecke Rare Book and Manuscript Library
- Authors and Illustrators for Children, 1719-2001; Series I; 8.38; (21 boxes)
  - Burgess, Gelett
    - Manuscript, "The Twins's [sic] Party by Cousin Virginia Goop"; manuscript song, undated (Box 4, Folder 77)
    - Postcard, to Tudor Jenks, regarding St. Nicholas Magazine, 1898 Dec 3 (Box 4, Folder 78)
  - Burgess, Thornton W. (Thornton Waldo)
    - Letter to Bernard M. Meeks regarding children and reading, 1950 Dec 9 (Box 5, Folder 79)
  - Burnett, Frances Hodgson
    - Letters (3) to an unidentified recipient regarding her method of writing, and to Kate Douglas Wiggin, 1894-1917 (Box 5, Folder 80)
  - Buskett, William C.
    - Letter to W. K. Bixby, regarding his friendship with Eugene Field and the poem "Penn Yan Bill", 1904 Feb 9 (Box 5, Folder 81)
      Removed from Shirley +362
  - Cady, Harrison
    - Drawings (2) for "The Happychaps," by Carolyn Wells; ink and pencil on bristol board, circa 1908
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, November 1908 and January 1909
    - Drawings (15) for Little Pete's Adventure, by Thornton Burgess; ink and pencil on paper, circa 1941 (Box 5, Folder 82)
    - Painting, "The Artist in his Studio"; oil on Masonite, framed, undated
      Inscribed on verso: Presented to Paul Bransom, April 10, 1966
    - Documents related to the estate of Harrison Cady, 1970-1971 (Box 5, Folder 83)
    - Letters (9) to Harriet and Stow Wengenroth, with postcards (9) related to the Audubon Artists, and papers related to the Rockport Art Association, 1946-1984 (Box 5, Folder 84)
  - Capote, Truman
    - Drawing of sailboat; crayon and pencil on paper, inscribed on verso to Duncan Frizzell, [1934] (Box 5, Folder 85)
    - Manuscript, "The Teacher's Tortured mind (or) The night Before Vacation"; typescript, corrected, [1936-1939] (Box 5, Folder 86)
    - Newspaper, The Trinity Times, New York; high school paper with contributions by and about Capote, 1933-1934
  - Carroll, Lewis
    Related Archival Materials note
    See: Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge
  - Castlemon, Harry
    - Autograph signatures (3 on 1 sheet), undated (Box 5, Folder 87)
  - Champney, James Wells
    - Drawings (3) for Being a Boy, by Charles Dudley Warner; ink on paper, circa 1878 (Box 5, Folder 88)
  - Chapman, J. G. (John Gadsby)
    - Proof impressions (91 on 44 sheets) of illustrations for A Christmas Gift from Fairy Land, by James K. Paulding, [1838?] (Box 5, Folder 89)
  - Child, Lydia Maria Francis
    - Poems, "To George Thompson," with on verso, "To an Afflicted Protestant Lady in France"; holograph, 1835 Aug 19 (Box 5, Folder 90)
  - Church, Frederick S. (Frederick Stuart)
    - Letters (29) to Evelyn Baker Schley Behr, 1906-1917, undated (Box 5, Folder 91)
    - Letters and notes (4) to Lisbeth Schley Behr and Evelyn Shirley Behr, 1914, undated (Box 5, Folder 92)
    - Letters (12) to Grant B. and Elizabeth Baker Schley, with letters (7) addressed to "Cousin", 1899-1904, undated (Box 5, Folder 93)
  - Clemens, Olivia Langdon
    - Letter to Mary Mapes Dodge, regarding Susy Clemens, 1896 Oct 25 (Box 5, Folder 94)
  - Clemens, Samuel Langhorne
    - Letters (2) to Olivia Susan (Susy) Clemens, regarding finances and activities in New York, and from "Santa Claus," with two postcard views of the Clemens home in Hartford, Connecticut, 1893 Nov 6, undated (Box 5, Folder 95)
    - Letters (2) to Librarian of Congress, and Charles Scribners' Sons, 1893, undated (Box 5, Folder 96)
    - Letters (2) to Asa Don Dickinson, regarding the banning of The Adventures of Tom Sawyer and The Adventures of Huckleberry Finn at Brooklyn Public Library, with newspaper clippings about the incident, 1906-1935 (Box 5, Folder 97)
  - Coffin, Hannah
    - Manuscript book, "A Collection of Sentence's [sic] Divine and Moral"; holograph with illustrations in ink, 1807 (Box 5, Folder 98)
  - Cogger, Edward P.
    - Proofs (16), hand-colored, for The Queen of Hearts and the Damson Tarts, 1867, 1869 (Box 5, Folder 99-100)
    - Drawing for title page for The Queen of Hearts; ink, blue pencil, and collage on stipple paper, circa 1891 (Box 5, Folder 101)
  - Colwell, William
    - Manuscript book, "The History of Birds, in Verse and Prose"; holograph, illustrated, 1794 (Box 5, Folder 102)
  - Coolidge, Susan
    - Manuscript, "Hodge the Cat," about Samuel Johnson's cat; holograph, undated (Box 5, Folder 103)
  - Cox, Palmer
    Arranged under three headings: The Brownies, The Greenies, and Miscellaneous
    - The Brownies
      - Drawings (34 on 16 sheets) for The Brownies Abroad; ink and pencil on bristol board mounted on illustration board, circa 1899 (Box 6, Folder 104)
      - Drawings (2) for "The Brownies Aid the Hospital"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 105)
        Numbers 3 and 6, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, February 1910
      - Drawing for "The Brownies Aid the Nursery"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 106)
        Number 7, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, November 1910
      - Drawings (2) for "The Brownies and the Library"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1911 (Box 6, Folder 107)
        Numbers 4 and 6, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, February 1911
      - Drawings (3) for "The Brownies and the Pure Milk Supply"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 108)
        Numbers 6, 7, and 8, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, July 1910
      - Drawings (4) for "The Brownies' Ice Harvest"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 109)
        Numbers 3, 4, 5, and 7, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, March 1910
      - Drawings (2) for "The Brownies' Quilting Bee"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1910
        Numbers 1 and 7, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, January 1910
      - Drawing for "The Brownies Repair the Streets"; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1910 (Box 6, Folder 110)
        Number 7, published in St. Nicholas Magazine, December 1910
      - Drawings (2) for "Brownie Scroll Puzzles: Blindman's Buff and the Dance," manufactured by McLoughlin Bros., New York; ink and watercolor on paper, circa 1891
      - Drawings (3) for "Brownie Scroll Puzzles: Hauling the Yule Log and Christmas Dinner," manufactured by McLoughlin Bros., New York; ink and watercolor on paper, circa 1891
        Includes drawing for box cover
      - Drawings (23 on 8 sheets) of Brownies for miscellaneous/unidentified projects; ink and pencil on bristol board mounted on paper, undated (Box 6, Folder 111)
      - Drawings of Brownies with personal notes (9) for Kathleen Smith; ink and watercolor on paper; with photographs of Cox and his home, "Brownie Castle," in Granby, Quebec, Canada, 1912-1921, undated (Box 6, Folder 112)
      - Drawings (20) of Brownies, as caricatures of international ethnic types; pencil and watercolor on paper, undated (Box 6, Folder 113)
        Drawn for Kathleen Smith
    - The Greenies
      - Drawings (14 on 12 sheets) for August Flower and German Syrup Almanac, for the G. G. Green Company; ink and pencil on paper, mounted on paper, circa 1890 (Box 6, Folder 114)
      - Drawings (15) for Wit and Wisdom Well Worth Reading; Containing the Greenies at Home, for the G. G. Green Company; ink and pencil on paper mounted on paper, circa 1890 (Box 6, Folder 115)
    - Miscellaneous
      - Drawing, portrait of "Twinkie"; pencil on bristol board, 1879 (Box 6, Folder 116)
      - Manuscript and drawings (62) for How Columbus Found America; ink and pencil on paper, circa 1876 (Box 6, Folder 117-119)
      - Letter from Annis Dunbar Jenkins, enclosing her issue of "The Browny", 1893 (Box 6, Folder 120)
      - Drawing [after Cox] of Brownies and New Year greeting from Julia Cain, undated (Box 6, Folder 121)
  - Crane, Walter
    - Agreement with John Lane Company regarding three books, 1910 May 9 (Box 6, Folder 122)
    - Drawings (2 on 1 sheet) of "U.S. Waiter" and a tailpiece design; ink on bristol board, undated (Box 6, Folder 123)
  - Crane, William D.
    - Manuscript book, "The Little Girl Who Loved Color and What Happened to Her"; typescript, with printed illustrations by Grandma Moses affixed to pages; autographed by Grandma Moses, undated (Box 6, Folder 124)
  - Cruikshank, George
    - Drawing, "Bacchanalian Composition"; pencil and watercolor on paper, undated
  - Dahl, Roald
    - Letter to Blanche Campbell, regarding Charlie and the Great Glass Elevator, 1972 Mar 3 (Box 7, Folder 125)
  - Dana, Richard Henry
    - Letter to unidentified British man, regarding Robert Southey, Henry W. Longfellow, Charles Sumner, and Joseph Story, among other topics, 1843 Jun 28 (Box 7, Folder 126)
  - Darley, Felix Octavius Carr
    The drawings are primarily sketches for illustrations of literary works; many were drawn on scraps of paper, or on the verso of forms such as bills of lading; several have additional and partial sketches on their versos
    - Drawings (57) in bound album; pencil and wash on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 127)
      With letters from Jane Colburn Darley, J. W. Bouton, and W. K. Bixby attesting to the album's authenticity
    - Drawing for Barnaby Rudge, by Charles Dickens; pencil and white chalk on paper, undated
    - Drawings (5) for The Big Bear of Arkansas, and Other Sketches, W. T. Porter, ed.; ink and wash on paper, circa 1845 (Box 7, Folder 128)
      See also: Darley album, folder 127
    - Drawings (5) for Great Expectations, The Old Curiosity Shop, and Oliver Twist, by Charles Dickens; pencil on paper, ink and wash on paper, undated
    - Drawings (2) for Ivanhoe, by Sir Walter Scott; pencil on paper, with tear sheet of one printed illustration, undated (Box 7, Folder 129)
    - Drawing, "Old Pastor & wife," for Margaret, by Sylvester Judd; pencil on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 130)
      Inscribed on verso: "Study for outline - but finished for pleasure/ F. O. C. Darley"
    - Drawings (4) for Pickings from the Portfolio of the Reporter of the New Orleans "Picayune"; pencil, ink, and wash on paper, circa 1846 (Box 7, Folder 131)
    - Drawing, sketch of trial scene from The Pickwick Papers, by Charles Dickens; pencil and white crayon on paper, undated
      Drawing of two Indians on verso
    - Drawing for Streaks of Squatter Life; ink, pencil, and wash on paper, with tear sheet of printed illustration, circa 1843 (Box 7, Folder 132)
    - Drawings (2) for The Theatrical Apprenticeship and Anecdotical Recollections of Sol. Smith; pencil, ink, and wash on paper, circa 1846 (Box 7, Folder 133)
    - Drawings (2) for Wing and Wing, by James Fenimore Cooper; sepia wash and pencil on bristol board, circa 1860
    - Drawing, farm scene; wash on Turnbull's Superfine London Board, undated (Box 7, Folder 134)
    - Drawing, "Figures used in 'Foraging Party' Large India Ink drawing for the late Wm. T. Blodgett"; pencil on paper, undated
    - Drawing, "Gypsy children at play"; pencil on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 135)
    - Drawing, "Komstok's Fonetik Magazin" cover design; ink, pencil, and wash on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 136)
    - Drawing, "Study for picture Return from Battlefield," pencil on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 137)
    - Drawing, "Twelve O'Clock"; ink on paper, 1840 (Box 7, Folder 138)
    - Drawings (3) of domestic scenes with children; pencil and white chalk on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 139)
    - Drawing of harvest scene, captioned "For Bank note co."; pencil on paper, undated
      On verso: sketch of graveyard scene (?)
    - Drawings (7) of rural agricultural scenes; pencil, ink, and wash on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 140)
      On verso of one: sketch of man slouched in chair
    - Drawings (3) of medieval scenes: castle, and knight on horse, woman kneeling; pencil on paper, undated (Box 7, Folder 141)
    - Drawings (3) of Revolutionary War scenes: battle, regiment marching, and officer in boat; pencil and wash on paper, 1840, undated (Box 7, Folder 142)
    - Drawings (2) of men in eighteenth-century costume; pencil and wash on paper, 1840-1846 (Box 7, Folder 143)
    - Drawings (19), miscellaneous sketches for unidentified projects; pencil, ink, wash, and crayon on paper, 1840s, undated (Box 7, Folder 144)
    - Drawing, possibly for James Fenimore Cooper novel; ink and wash on illustration board, 1878
    - Drawing, figure sketches for unidentified project; pencil on illustration board, undated
    - Letters (2) to James L. Graham and to Miss Vickers, regarding the "Travellers Club" and an autograph of Henry W. Longfellow, 1865, 1881 (Box 7, Folder 145)
  - Daugherty, James Henry
    - Drawing, "Abraham Lincoln comforting the wounded at Gettysburg," for Abraham Lincoln; pencil and red pencil on paper, circa 1943
    - Drawing, "Democracy"; ink and opaque white on paper, 1944
  - Dickens, Charles
    - Letter to S. Arthur Chappell, regarding receipt of payment for readings, 1867 Jun 3 (Box 7, Folder 146)
  - Denslow, W. W. (William Wallace)
    - Drawing, "Captain Bing was a Pirate King...," for Father Goose: His Book, by L. Frank Baum; ink, gouache, black chalk and pencil on paper, 1899
    - Drawing for dust jacket for Father Goose: His Book, by L. Frank Baum; ink and black chalk on paper, 1899
    - Drawing for alternate title page for The Songs of Father Goose, by L. Frank Baum and Alberta N. Hall; ink and pencil on paper, 1900
    - Drawing for end papers for Denslow's Mother Goose; ink and pencil on paper, 1901
  - Dodge, Mary Mapes
    - Draft of letter to Samuel Clemens, regarding Tom Sawyer, [1892] Nov 20 (Box 7, Folder 147)
  - Dodgson, Charles Lutwidge
    - Letter to Mary Jackson, regarding Isa Bowman, 1889 Nov 23 (Box 7, Folder 148)
    - Letter to the Lowrie children, with "Mischmasch," printed word-game, inscribed by Dodgson, l884 Aug 18 (Box 7, Folder 149)
    - Letter to Alexander Macmillan, regarding the American edition of Alice's Adventures in Wonderland, 1870 Feb 7 (Box 7, Folder 150)
  - Doepler, Carl Emil
    - Proof of engraved frontispiece from unidentified family atlas; engraved by C. Wise, circa 1850
  - Drayton, Grace G.
    - Drawing of child in swimsuit with bucket and spade; ink and watercolor on illustration board, undated (Box 8, Folder 151)
    - Drawings (48) for four sets of "Dimples" cartoons; ink and pencil on bristol board, mounted in one bound volume, 1913-1914 (Box 8, Folder 152)
  - Du Bois, William Pène
    - Drawing for Elisabeth the Cow Ghost; ink, watercolor, and crayon on bristol board, circa 1936 (Box 8, Folder 153)
    - Drawing for Giant Otto; watercolor and ink on illustration board, circa 1936 (Box 8, Folder 154)
  - Du Chaillu, Paul B. (Paul Belloni)
    - Letter to Mrs. Mitchell, regarding his life in Russia, 1902 Nov 21 (Box 8, Folder 155)
  - Earle, Alice Morse
    - Letters to Andrew White Tuer (5) and unidentified friend (1) regarding her books, 1899-1904 (Box 8, Folder 156)
  - Eaton, Caroline Ketcham
    - Manuscript book, "Illustrated Alphabet for Little Folks"; ink and watercolor on paper, circa 1890
  - Eichenberg, Fritz
    - Drawing of boy with goat presenting bird to queen; ink on bristol board, undated
    - Letter to Sybille A. Jagusch, Library of Congress, regarding his visit and a drawing, 1985 Oct 25 (Box 8, Folder 157)
  - Eliot, T. S. (Thomas Stearns)
    - Letter to Mrs. Muller, regarding publication of Old Possum's Book of Practical Cats, 1939 Feb 9 (Box 8, Folder 158)
  - Falls, C. B. (Charles Buckles)
    - Account statements from The A.B.C. Book, 1924-1938 (Box 8, Folder 159)
    - Proof prints (3) for The A.B.C. Book; color and black-and-white woodcuts, circa 1923
  - Fame's Tribute to Children
    - Collection of sentiments (16) contributed by writers to raise funds for the Children's Home, World's Columbian Exposition; holographs, 1892 (Box 8, Folder 160)
      Authors include Margaret Deland, Austin Dobson, Millicent Garrett Fawcett, R.W. Gilder, Julian Hawthorne, Jean Ingelow, Joseph Jefferson, Benjamin Jowett, Justin McCarthy, Richard Mansfield, M. J. Meath, George Meredith, Thomas Nelson Page, Joseph Henry Shorthouse, Edmund Clarence Stedman, and Edith M. Thomas
  - Field, Eugene
    - Manuscript, "Extinct Monsters"; holograph poem with ink drawings, 1895 Oct
    - Manuscript, "When Willie wet the bed"; typescript poem, 1895 Oct 19 (Box 8, Folder 161)
      Removed from Shirley 3218
  - Finley, Martha
    - Agreement regarding Elsie Dinsmore and sequel Hollidays [sic] at Roseland, and copyright form, and portrait photograph, 1868, undated (Box 8, Folder 162)
  - Ford, Paul Leicester
    - Documents (7) regarding The New-England Primer, 1897-1901 (Box 8, Folder 163)
  - Fox, Fontaine
    - Drawing of a trolley; ink on card stock, undated (Box 8, Folder 164)
  - Francis, J. G. (Joseph Greene)
    - Scrapbook with drawings (16), clippings, and a letter to Francis, compiled by Fannie E. Morrill (died 1882), 1879-1884 (Box 8, Folder 165)
  - Frost, A. B. (Arthur Burdett)
    - Drawing, "He Wasn't as Tired as He Looked"; ink on bristol board, 1890
      Published in Harper's Young People, October 7, 1890
    - Drawing for Farming, by Richard Munkittrick; ink on paper, circa 1892
    - Drawings (2) for Uncle Remus, His Songs and Sayings, by Joel Chandler Harris; ink on paper, circa 1895
  - Gág, Wanda
    - Letter to an unidentified recipient, regarding German fairy tales, undated (Box 9, Folder 166)
    - Drawings (2) for Snow White and the Seven Dwarfs; pencil, watercolor, and ink on paper, circa 1938
  - Gardner, Eliza
    - Manuscript book, "Juvenile Stories"; holograph with illustrations; with manuscript poem "The Rainbow", 1829, undated (Box 9, Folder 167)
  - Gladstone, W. E. (William Ewart)
    - Essay, "Personal recollections of Arthur Henry Hallam"; holograph, bound with an extra-illustrated published version, "Arthur Henry Hallam," reprinted from the Youth's Companion, January 6, 1898, 1896, 1898
  - Goodrich, Samuel G. (Samuel Griswold)
    - Manuscript copy of copyright certificate for Peter Parley's Gift, with photograph of silhouette by Augustin Edouart, issued by Emily Jackson, 1839, circa 1930 (Box 9, Folder 168)
  - Goodwin, Polly
    - Letters (41) from various authors, regarding the most important books from their childhood, 1958, 1967 (Box 9, Folder 169-170)
      Data collected for two articles written for the Chicago Tribune; authors include Cleveland Amory, Ludwig Bemelmans, Gwendolyn Brooks, Ilka Chase, John Ciardi, Loren Eiseley, Clifton Fadiman, Edna Ferber, Ernest Hemingway, Bel Kaufman, James Michener, Marianne Moore, Ogden Nash, Carl Sandburg, Charles M. Schulz, William Styron, Gore Vidal, Thornton Wilder, and Jessamyn West.
  - Goulding, Matilda Rees
    - Agreement with Dodd, Mead & Company for The Young Marooners, 1887 Mar 3 (Box 9, Folder 171)
  - Grace, Mary
    - Mechanicals (2) for a "Sesame Street" holiday card by Drawing Board Greeting Cards, Inc.; ink, watercolor, and photocopy on illustration board, 1979 (Box 9, Folder 172)
  - Grahame, Elspeth
    - Letter to Mrs. Laurence R. Thomsen, regarding autograph for Thomsen's child; also tells story, 1946 Apr 6 (Box 9, Folder 173)
  - Grahame, Kenneth
    - Letters to Ruth Greenough, regarding relationship of The Wind in the Willows to Gibbon's Decline and Fall of the Roman Empire, and to Robert Underwood Johnson, regarding Johnson's The Varmint, 1906, 1912 (Box 9, Folder 174)
  - Gramatky, Hardie
    - Drawing, "Little Toot"; pastel on paper, framed, undated
  - Grant, Campbell
    See: Walt Disney Productions
  - Grayson, Harry, and Maurice Rapkin
    - Manuscript book, "Engineer Pete and his Foolish Questions," with ink illustrations, undated
  - Greenwood, Edna Muriel Hilburn Little
    - Correspondence and notes regarding American primers and George Thompson, 1934-1955, undated (Box 9, Folder 175)
  - Griswold, Rufus W. (Rufus Wilmot)
    - Letter to Carey and Hart, regarding typography for and delay in production of the first edition of The Poets and Poetry of America, 1842 Oct 7 (Box 9, Folder 176)
      Removed from Shirley 3497
  - Gruelle, Johnny
    - Drawing for covers for Raggedy Andy Stories; watercolor, ink, and pencil on bristol board, circa 1920
    - Drawings (2) of Raggedy Ann and Andy; gouache, ink, colored pencil, and collage on illustration board, circa 1920
    - Letter from Myrtle Gruelle to Beatrice Doe and school children, regarding her life, 1958 Mar 4 (Box 9, Folder 177)
  - Guthrie, Charles John Guthrie, Lord
    - Essay, "Mrs Robert Louis Stevenson," clipped from The Scotsman, 1914 Feb 24 (Box 9, Folder 178)
      Removed from Shirley 3650
  - Habberton, John
    - Copyright certificate for Helen's Babies, 1907 Oct 2 (Box 9, Folder 179)
    - Manuscript, "Forward (to 'Author's Edition of Helen's Babies')"; holograph, 1907 (Box 9, Folder 180)
  - Hale, Edward Everett
    - Letter to unidentified man, regarding "The Story of Philip Nolan," and two autographed notes, 1864-1890 (Box 9, Folder 181)
  - Hale, Sarah Josepha Buell
    - Manuscript, "Mary's Lamb"; holograph, 1865 Jan 23 (Box 9, Folder 182)
    - Letter from Mary Sawyer Tyler to J. Dewitt Miller, regarding "Mary's Lamb," with a transcript of the poem, yarn spun from the lamb's fleece, and a photograph of Tyler, 1878-1879, undated (Box 9, Folder 183)
    - Letter from Horatio Hale to J. Dewitt Miller, regarding "Mary's Lamb," with annotations in a second hand (possibly Miller's), 1879 Apr 10 (Box 9, Folder 184)
    - Manuscript, "Mary's Lamb" in dialects of French, Chinese, Dutch, and Irish, undated (Box 9, Folder 185)
    - Union case with image of Mary and her lamb, made by Littlefield, Parsons & Co., containing ruby ambrotype portrait of an unidentified woman, circa 1857 (Box 9, Folder 186)
  - Halm, George R.
    - Drawings (2) for "Answered Riddle Jingles"; ink and pencil on bristol board, circa 1886
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, February 1886
  - Harrington, Alice H.
    - Manuscript, "The Sylvan Party"; holograph, 1879 (Box 9, Folder 187)
      See also: Box 9, folder 196
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, July 1879
  - Haven, Alice B. (Alice Bradley)
    - Letters (2) to unidentified publisher, regarding chapter submissions, 1856 (Box 9, Folder 188)
  - Hawthorne, Julian
    - Letter to Mr. Strahan, regarding payment for a forthcoming work and inviting Strahan to visit; accompanied by five clippings concerning Nathaniel Hawthorne and Brook Farm, 1875, 1890 (Box 9, Folder 189)
      Removed from Shirley 3496
  - Hawthorne, Nathaniel
    - Letter to Maria Louisa Hawthorne, regarding children, housing, and family matters, 1851 Jul 10 (Box 9, Folder 190)
  - Hemingway, Ernest
    - Letter to Emily, regarding a variety of school topics, [1916?] (Box 9, Folder 191)
  - Henson, Jim and Jane
    - Letter to Corinne R. Manning, regarding Kermit the Frog, "signed" also by the Muppets; with postcard of the Muppets, 1961 Feb 1 (Box 9, Folder 192)
  - Herford, Oliver
    - Drawing, "Scene II"; ink and pencil on bristol board, undated
  - Hochstein, Anthony
    - Drawings (3), "A Justice of the Peace," "The Concert, Unisono," and "Scare crow"; watercolor and ink on paper, undated (Box 9, Folder 193)
  - Holmes, Oliver Wendell
    - Documents (2) regarding publication of Grandmother's Story of the Battle of Bunker Hill, 1883 (Box 9, Folder 194)
  - Hopkins, Livingston
    - Drawing for "Dumb Orator" by Christopher P. Cranch; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1877 (Box 9, Folder 195)
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, July 1877
    - Drawings (5) for "The Sylvan Party," by Alice Harrington; ink and pencil on bristol board, 1879 (Box 9, Folder 196)
      See also: Box 9, folder 187
      Published in St. Nicholas Magazine, June 1879
    - Drawings (44) for The Story of a Cat, by Emile de la Bédollière, translated from the French by T. B. Aldrich; ink and pencil on bristol board, circa 1878 (Box 9, Folder 197-199)